Sonnenstuhl, William Papers /4312
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
William Sonnenstuhl Papers
1987-1999
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Sonnenstuhl, William
/4312
10 cubic feet
4 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
8507381
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 24, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 05, 2016
Biographical / Historical
William Sonnenstuhl is an Associate Professor in the Department of Organizational Behavior and the Department of Extension. He received his Ph.D. in Sociology from New York University in 1983 and his M.A. in Sociology from the New York School for Social Research in 1971. Professor Sonnenstuhl teaches course in Organizational Behavior. These include: Cultures of Work Organizations, Organizations and Deviance, and Research Methods. He is also Associate Director of the ILR School's R. Brinkley Smithers Institute for Alcohol-Related Workplace Studies, where he conducts research on substance abuse and the workplace and education programs for labor and management.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4313: Harrison Trice Papers
Sonnenstuhl, William J., 1946-; Trice, harrison Miller, 1920-
8507381
- journals, books (Box 1)
  - Christopher D. Smithers Foundation, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Alcohol in Italian Culture 1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Marijuana 1969 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Practical Alcoholism Programming 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Heroin and Behaviour, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Para-Professional in the Treatment of Alcoholism, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Biology of Alcoholism: Vol. 3 Clinical Pathology, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ceremonial Chemistry 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Biology of Alcoholism: Vol 5 Treatment and Rehabilitation of the Chronic Alcoholic, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Professional and Para-Professional Drug Abuse Counselors: Three Reports 1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Alcoholism in Women 1980 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Register on United Kingdom Alcohol Research 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Cocaine Use in America 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Drugs in the Workplace, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Initial Sensitivity to Alcohol 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Drug Abuse Pervention Intervention Research: Methodological Issues 1991 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- EAP training materials (Box 2)
  - Improving Drug Treatment 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - A Promising Future: Alcohol and other Drug Problem Prevention Services Improvement 1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - A Training Course for EAP Referral Agents 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - A Training Course for EAP Referral Agents, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The 1982 Report on Drug Abuse and Alcoholism (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Alcoholism: Films and Education, Training and Treatment, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Employee Assistance Programs: A Survey of Business Experience, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Five-Year Comprehensive Plan for Alcoholism Services in New York State 1984-1989, 1986-1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Alcohol and Drugs: Programmes of Assistance for Workers, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Innovations in Organizations: The Internal and External Marketing or EAP's [Folder 1 of 2], 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Innovations in Organizations: The Internal and External Marketing on EAP's [Folder 2 of 2], 1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Level 1 EAP Educational Materials (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Operation: Red Block, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - American Labor History Spring 1988 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - American Labor History [Folder 1 of 2] Fall 1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - American Labor History [Folder 2 of 2] Fall 1988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Serving Alcohol with care: Leader's Guide 1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Serving Alcohol with Care: Server's Manual 1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- EAP training materials (Box 3)
  - Statewide Employee Assistance Program: Program Manual 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Statewide Employee Assistance Program Train-the-Trainer Manual, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Work Organizations and Troubled Employees Session 1-8 [Folder 1 of 2] 1988 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Work Organizations and Troubled Employees Sessions 1-8 [Folder 2 of 2] 1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Work Organizations and Troubled Employees Participant's Manual 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Work Organizations and Troubled Employees Participant's Manual, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Clinical Issues Sessions 3-5 1989 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Clinical Issues: Sessions 6-12 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Basic Union Counselor Training 1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Citizen's Alcohol and Other Drug Prevention Directory 1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Extending the Alcohol and Drug Free Workplace to Smaller Work Organizations 1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Five-Year Comprehensive Plan For Alcoholism Services in New York State 1990 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Core Technology as a Basic for Certifying Employee Assistance, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Association or Flight Attendants EAP Resource Manual [Folder 1 of 2], 1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Association of Flight Attendants EAP [Folder 2 of 2], 1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Coordination of Alcohol, Drug Abuse, and Mental Health Services 1991 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - The Future by Design, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - National Household Survey on Drug Abuse; Main Findings 1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - National Household Survey an Drug Abuse: Population Estimate 1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Policy Statement and Guidelands on Joint Union/Management Employee and Family Assistance Programs (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Substance Abuse in the Transit Industry 1991 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - What Works; Workplaces Without Alcohol and other Drugs 1991 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Our Tradition of Caring (Box 3, Folder 23)
- training manuals (Box 4)
  - Alcohol/ Substance Abuse Program 1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Association of Flight Attendants EAP Resources Manual [Folder 1 of 2] 1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Association of Flight Attendants EAP Resource Manual [Folder 2 of 2] 1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - International Labour Office 1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Need, Demand, and Problem Agreement for Substance Abuse Services 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Self-Run, Self-Supported Houses for More Effective Recovery from Alcohol and Drug Addiction 1992 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Substance Abuse: The Labor Movement Approach 1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - The American with Disabilities Act: what the Labor Assistance Professional Needs to Know 1993 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Labor Assistance Professionals Workshop series: Labor Assistance Professional: The History are Helping Ourselves 1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Labor Assistance Professionals Workshop Series: Recovery/Release Prevention 1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Labor Assistance Professionals workshop Series: Interventions Workshop 2 1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Labor Assistance Professionals Workshop Series: Drug Testing and the EAP Workshops 3 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Labor Assistance Professionals Workshops Series: Domestic Violence and HIV/AIDS Workshops 4 1993 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Labor Assistance Professionals Workshops Series: Workplace Series and the EAP Workship 5 1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Labor Assistance Professional Workshop Series Transparencies 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - "Managed Care" From a Union Perspective (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Promoting Intervention/ Using the Program 1993 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Railroads/UTU 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Worksite Initiative to Promote Speedriving 1994 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Five-Year Comprehensive Plan for Alcohol and Substance Abuse Services 1994-1999 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Summary of the Principal Findings: The Health Care Intervention Service Program Evaluation 1995 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - UTU Regional Meeting Seminar Materials [Folder 1 of 2] 1996 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - UTU Regional Meeting Seminar Materials [Folder 2 of 2] 1996 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Labor Assistance Professionals EAP Curriculum Copy 2 1999 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Labor Assistance Professionals EAP Curriculum Copy 2 1999 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Developing an Employee Assistance Program (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Mining Industry Resource Manual on Alcohol and Drug Abuse (Box 4, Folder 27)